Guide to the Harold E. Klein papers, 1980-1993.
Klein, Harold E. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harold E. Klein papers, 1980-1993.
6796
Klein
6 cubic feet.
Correspondence printed material, publications, photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection includes reports, correspondence, documents, official publications, photographs and statements pertaining to Burma and the American Karen Agency from Klein's time as the Director of Human Rights for the AKA.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harold Eugene Klein was born in 1926 in Greeley, Colorado. His parents were missionaries to Burma, where he grew up until moving back to the USA in 1940. He attended Denison University, before transferring to University of Redlands, and once more to UC Berkeley, where he graduated with a BA in Political Science. He also obtained his Teacher's Credential with studies at UCLA, as well as a Masters of Arts from Long Beach State University and a began (but never completed) his Ph.D. at UCLA. Klein worked as a high school teacher until his retirement in 1985. Following his retirement, he began working with the American Karen Agency as the Director of Human Rights, raising funds and goods for refugee camps, hospitals, and schools in Burma.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection includes reports, correspondence, documents, official publications, photographs and statements pertaining to Burma and the American Karen Agency from Klein's time as the Director of Human Rights for the AKA. Notable among the papers are letters to and from politicians, including senators, representatives, and the President. Also includes material from The Overseas Burma Liberation Organization, Karen Human Rights Group, and Amnesty International.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Klein, Harold E.; American Karen Agency.; Amnesty International.; Karen Human Rights Group.; Overseas Burma Liberation Organization.
Subjects:
Human rights -- Burma.; Karen (Southeast Asian people)
Places:
Burma.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters from Thailand, 1982-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Letters from Thailand to Harold Klein
- Misc. Correspondences, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people
  Letters from people to Harold Klein
  List about Keren Names and addresses in USA
  Articles
  Information about family tree of Rev. Saw Tun Sein
  Appendix about delta self support rural rehabilitation and human development project
  Refugee inquiry sheet (near East and South Asia) from Church World Service
  Ohn Han’s Curriculum Vitae
  Copies of certification from United Nations
  Application for resettlement in the States
  Appendix about Karen rural development Chris`tn center project
  An Eyewitness Account of the Damages and Loss of Lives Suffered by Villagers in the Delta Area During Fighting with the SLORC Army. 1991. Dawn News Bulletin Vol.3 No.6
  The Massacre of Karen People in Irrawaddy Division by Military Dictators (October 1991) (Burma)
- Misc. Correspondences, continued, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Misc. Correspondences, continued, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondences in USA, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Faxes from Harold Klein to people
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. President Bill Clinton, United States Senators, and Congressmen)
  Letters from people (e.g. United States Senators) to Harold Klein
  Letter of special credential from Saw Maw Reh, President in the Government of Karenni
  Biography and Resume of Harold E. Klein
- Correspondences in USA, continued, 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Misc. Correspondences, 1984-2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  World News
- Misc. Letters and Papers, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Paper about An Oppressive Regime Withstanding the March of Freedom: Burma by Helge Philipp Boes in Georgia State University in 1991
- Misc. Letters and information, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Letter from Harold Klein to Congressman Tom Lantos
  Information
  Democratic alliance of Burma
  Organization committee for restoration democracy in Burma
  Organization of opposition groups to Burmese government
- Correspondence and Photos, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Letters from people in Thailand to Harold Klein
  Transcript of Tape
  Budget proposal for teacher training
  program – 1991-1992 school year6
  Photos
- Correspondences, 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Letters from people (e.g. Secretary of Committee for Development Planning on the United Nations) to Harold Klein
  Name of Japanese Diet Members who submitted the petition to United Nations Secretary General
- Correspondences, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letters from people (e.g. California State Senator) to Harold Klein
- Flash News Service Reports, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Overseas Burmese Reaction to the NCG formation
  The SLORC’s “Open Economy”
  Making Peach in Burma
  High-Flying U.N Officials in Burma
  The Prospect of National Unity in Burma
- Letter to Martin Abramowitz, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Letter from Harold Klein to Martin Abramowitz, President of Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
- Burma Center Faxes, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Faxes from Harold Klein to people (Sweden Democratic Burma)
  Faxes from people (Sweden Democratic Burma) to Harold Klein
- Faxes to senators, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Faxes from Harold Klein to senators
- Correspondences, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Letter to Matthew Giuffrida, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Letters from Harold Klein to Matthew Giuffrida, Director of Immigration and Refugee Services
- Letters to Politicians, 1988-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Amnesty International, 1995-2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1980 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Karen Tapes Translation
  Burma Focus Published by the All Burma Students’ Democratic Front Vol. 7 No.3 in 1993
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. Margaret Thatcher, Prime Minister of United Kingdom)
  News form South China Morning Post
  Address List of International Letters on Burma's “Poor Nation” Status
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Official Bulletin of International Council of Independent States
  News from OTAGO Daily Times in 1992
  The Human Rights Fact Sheets No. 7
  Letters from International Council of Independent States to people (e.g. Minister of Foreign Affairs)
  ICIS/UN 192
  Official Bulletin of Karenni Provisional Government
- Reports for AKA, 1990 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Reports
  An Analysis of Burma Event
  Observation on the Political Turmoil in Burma
  An Analysis of Trends in S.E. Asia – Burma – and U.S. Policy Thereto
  The Prospects for a Free Referendum
  The Truth Behind the Unification of Opposition to the BSPP
  Annual Report – Director of Human Rights – 1990-91
  Assessing the Burma (Myanmar) Situation - 1992
- Democratic Alliance of Burma, 1988 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  The Alliance Bulletin from 1989 to 1991
  Declaration of the Democratic Alliance of Burma
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. President George Bush)
  Letters from Democratic Alliance of Burma to people
  Statement of the Democratic – Alliance of Burma (DAB) on the Rangoon Military Junta’s Election Law
  Reports from Democratic Alliance of Burma
  Photos about Russian Type Shells
  News from Bangkok Post
  Statement on the Formation of the National Coalition Government of Burma
- Misc. Reports, 1987 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  The U.S. Committee for Refugees Reprint 1989-1990
  News from the U.S. Committee for Refugees 1990
  Refugee Reports
  Roger P. Winter. 1987. "The Karens of Burma: Victims of War. The World and I"
  Roger P. Winter. "The Karens of Burma: Thailand's Other Refugees"
- Misc. Reports, 1991 - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Thai-Yunnan Project Newsletter
  Far Easter Economic Review
  Report about Observation of Burma
  Asian Studies Newsletter
  Burma Book Review May 1993
  Thant Myint – U. 1992. "Bringing SLORC to heel." Far Eastern Economic Review.
  Bertil Lintner. 1992. "Collective insecurity." Far Eastern Economic Review
  Bertil Lintner. 1993. "Rangoon’s Rubicon." Far Eastern Economic Review.
- Answartiges AMT, 1987 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Letters from people (e.g. Answartiges AMT) to Harold Klein
- Photos and Name Card, 1988-2003 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Name Card
  Burmese Important List
- Miscellaneous Papers and Letters, 1952 - 2006 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Letter from Harold Klein to Congressman Joseph Pitts
  “Important History” (from AKA KYO)
  Others
- Misc. Papers and Proposals, 1995 – 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Application for funding to support certain Burma-related programs
  A Project Proposal for a Public General Hospital
  American Karen Agency Application for funding
- Miscellaneous Papers, 1987 - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Samaritan’s Purse 1987 – 1988
  Concordia Gospel Ministry 1990-1991
  Share in Prayer Bulletin 1990
  Newsletter of Northern California DX Foundation 1992-
  Media Release Issued by the Karen National Union on Burma’s State Law and Order Restoration Council Military offensive against K.N.U. Headquarters
  Special Health Report: Thai-Burmese Border and the Karen People
  A Brief History of the Karen and the Burmans Relationship
  News
  John B. Haseman. 1988. "Burma in 1987 Change in the Air?" ASIAN Survey Vol. XXVIII. No. 2
  "The World Press on Burma" by U Hla Shwe
  "Democracy for Burma Soon" by U Hla Shwe
  "The Universal Declaration of Human Rights – Implementation and Enforcement" By Harold E. Klein
- APACL Newsletter, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Letter from World Anti-Communist League to Harold Klein
  APACL Newsletter 1988 - 1989
- Misc. Papers, Articles, and Correspondences, 1987 - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Report from Economic and Social Council of the United Nations
  Foreign Companies Trading in Burma
  Associates to Develop Democratic Burma (ADDB) by Harn Yawnghwe
  The Tatmadaw Dictatorship: Evaluation and Conclusion
  Faxes from people to Harold Klein
  "Burma – the Sick Man of South East Asia" by Harold Klein
  "The Burman Military: Holding the Country Together?" By Chao Tzang Yawnghwe
- Aid to Artisans, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  News by Aid to Artisans in 1990
- Original Draft, "The Karen Nation – A Search for Freedom" (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Untitled 80 Page Paper (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Maps, 1967 and 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Map of Thailand, Laos, and Cambodia
  Map of Burma and Thailand
- Press Releases and News, 1995 - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  The BurmaNet News 1997
  U.S. Department of State Burma Report on Human Rights Practices for 1996
  International News
  "Myanmar Says U.N. envoy can visit in April" by Aung Hla Tun
  U.S. says Myanmar should let U.N. envoy visit
  Myanmar coup issue no bar to peace talks – U.N. envoy
  Myanmar tells UN envoy to postpone visit – sources
  "EU visit sheds little light on Myanmar future" by Aung Hla Tun and Andrew Marshall
  Myanmar General Appears After Coup
  Ex-Myanmar Dictator’s Kin To Be Tried
- Faxes and Correspondence, 1995 - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- The Burma Bulletin and Letters, 1977 - 1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  The Burma Bulletin 1977-1979
- Misc. News, Notes, and Letters, 1995 - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  USIS Washington File 1996
  "Significant Developments in SINO-Burma Relationship" by Oak Auw
- Helge Phi Boes's Honors Thesis, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  An Honors Thesis entitled “The Right to Union: The Concept of Self-Determination and the Karen of Burma”
- Research Papers, 1988 - 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  International Seminar on Asean and the Wider Southeast Asia 1990
  Research Papers
  Josef Silverstein. 1988. "Burma, July 1988: An Overview." Rutgers University
  Martin Smith. "Peach in Burma: A Possibility? The Position of the Armed Opposition Groups"
  David I. Steinberg. 1988. "The Play is over, but the audience is forced to remain in their seats, and the actors refuse to leave the stage"
  Robert H. Taylor. 1988." Draft for Discussion: Not for quotation or citation without the express written consent of the author." University of London.
- Misc. Papers and Letters, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  A Preliminary Checklist of Burma Holdings in NIU Libraries
  Announcements of Center for Burma Studies in 1987
  Bulletin of the Burma Studies Group 1987
  Understanding a Nation: Burma the Golden Land
- Congress, 1989 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  1989 Annual Report of Congressional Human Rights CAUCUS
  Letters from Congress of the United States to President George Bush
- Miscellany, 1991 - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Papers
  Map
  Logging Practices of S.E.Asia
  A brief summary of the history of the Karen National Union
  E-mail
  "Assessing the Burma (Myanmar) Situation" – 1992 by Harold E. Klein
  "When the general talk to ethnic rebels" by Yindee Lertcharoenchok in 1991
- Miscellany, 1990 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Declaration of the National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma
  Letters from National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma to people
  Personal Statement Regarding the SLORC’s National Convention by Khon Mar Ko Ban
  Agreement to Establish a Federal Union of Burma
- Karen Village Relocations and Massacres, 1991 – 1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Palaung Statements by Manerplaw in 1992
  Activities in the DELTA (IRRAWADDY) Area and Activities on the General Public
  The Present Day Plight of Delta Karens under the Dictatorship Military Regime
  Preliminary List of Villages Forced to Move in Bilin and Pa’an Townships of Thaton District
  Forced Relocation in Thaton District Preliminary Report by Menerplaw
  The Massacre of Karen People in Irrawaddy Division by Military Dictators
  An Eyewitness Account of the Damages and Loss of Life Suffered by Villagers in the Delta Area during fighting with the Burmese Army
- Draft Constitution and Newsletters, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Draft Constitution for Future Federal
  Union of Burma Proposed by Karen National Union
  The Burma Association Newsletter
- Karen Political Proclamations, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Health and Welfare System of the Karen National Union
  Health System in Kawthoolei published by Ministry of Health and Welfare Government of Kawthoolei
  Burma & US Congress on November 17, 1995
  Statement of Eleventh Congress of KNU
  Statement of Basic Position of NCUB With Regard to the Release of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi From Detention
  KNU Statement on Offensive of SLORC Against KNPP
- Political Statements, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Meeting of the Socialist International Asia-Pacific Committee in 1995
  Resolution on Burma in 1995
  Future of Democracy in Burma by U Win Khet
  A Statement on Continued Detention of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi and Human Rights Condition in Burma
- Myanmar Statement, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Introductory Statement by the Special Rapporteur on the Situation of Human Rights in Myanmar
- Misc. Papers and Reports, 1988 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Second Translation of Top Secret BSPP Plan
  The Last Stronghold of Democracy in Burma
  Burma News
  Burma and the United Nations: A Proposal for Constructive Involvement 1992
  News Bulletin 1989 - 1992
- Burma Interview and Review, 1990 – 1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Excerpts from interview with Alan Clements and U Sein Win, Prime Minister National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma in 1990
  The Crisis in Burma: A Summary
- Pacific-Asia Empowerment Reports, 1987 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Reports of Pacific-Asia Empowerment Conference
- Miscellany, 1990 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  National Refugee Week 1991
  The Official Newsletter of the Australian Board of Missions
- Miscellany, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Letters
- Misc. Letters and Papers, 1988 - 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  International Negotiation Network News 1992
  Conference Report Volume 5 of the Carter Center of Emory University 1993
- Misc. Correspondence and Papers, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  A Brief Explanation of Enclosed Documents
  The SLORC’s “Leave or Die” Ultimatum to Karenni Villagers
- Miscellany, 1991 – 2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Burma Support 2006
  Christian Freedom International Front Line New Page 1991
  Junta’s Crusade Against Christians by Benedict Rogers
  U.S. Department of State Annual Report on International Religious Freedom for 1999: Burma
- Correspondence, 1988 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  Postcard from Sao Ying Sita to Harold Klein
  Letters from people (e.g. Sao Ying Sita) to Harold Klein
  Letter from Harold to people (e.g. Prince Khaled Bin Sultan Bin Abdulaiz)
- Miscellany, 1994 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Reports from Economic and Social Council of the United Nations 1994 – 1997
  Report on Human Rights Abuses in Chin State and Northwestern Burma
  House of Lords Official Report 1995
  A day without fear - A life without fear
- Burma Democratic Council, 1990 - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. Congressional Representative in U.S.A.)
  Participating Organizations of International Burma Campaign
  Reports about Trail of Terror along Thai-Burmese Border by Denis D Gray
- Buddhist Peace Fellowship Newsletter, 1986 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Buddhist Peace Fellowship Newsletter 1986 - 1989
- Buddhist Peace Fellowship, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Letter from people to Harold Klein
  Draft of the Karen People’s Search for Freedom and Justice by Harold E. Klein
- Misc. Faxes and Reports, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Other reports
- Miscellany, 1990 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Faxes
- News releases, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  News releases in Canada
- Misc. Statements and Press Releases, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Report by U Aung Saw Oo
  Media Release about “Ours Are Not the Only Trees: Remember Burma” by Christabel Chamarette
  News Release about Myanmar: Fall of Manerplaw
  News Release about Australian Democrats: Bob Hawke and Burma
  News from the Carter Center
  Statement of the Kachin Independence Organization on the Current Military Offensive Against the Karen National Union
  Censorship Press Release
- Misc. Faxes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Background Materials (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Biography of Harold E. Klein
- Burmese Relief Center, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  The Burma Report 1991
- Ephemera (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Report about Sri Lanka – Victim of a Dee Colonialism
- Miscellaneous Papers and Reports, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  List of United States Senate
  List of United States House of Representatives
  List of Permanent Mission to United Nations
  Independent Reports by the Karen Human Rights Group (1995-1996)
  Monthly Reports by Karen Refugee Committee (1995-1998)
  Statement of Senator Mitch McConnell
  Anglo-Burmese Migration to Australia 1964-1972 by Calra Win Pe in 1987
- Miscellany, 1994 -1998 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. John Imle, President of UNOCAL)
  Paper about Memorandum from the Delta Karen of Burma
  Project Proposal for a General Hospital for Karen Population
  Paper about the Current Human Rights Situation in Burma by Kevin Heppner, Karen Human Rights Group
  Regional Scholarship Programs Supplementary Grant Program – Burma 1997/1998
  Proposed Communication Standard Operating Procedures
  The New Era Journal
- Miscellaneous Faxes and Papers (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Miscellany, 1995 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Faxes from Harold Klein to people (e.g. Congressmen)
  Faxes from people (e.g. United State Senators) to Harold Klein
  Amnesty International
  List of National League for Democracy Members of Parliament - Elect and Activists Arrested since 20 May 1996
  Monthly Report by Karen Refugee Committee (1995 - )
  Information of Burma Lesons
  The official transcript of the press conference
  Myanmar Ethnic minority rights under attack
  Myanmar/Bangladesh Rohingyas – The Search for Safety
  Kingdom of Thailand Erosion of Refugee Rights
  Myanmar Scores of Activists Detained
- Misc. Papers and Correspondences (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Misc. Papers and Correspondences, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. Secretary General of the United Nations)
  Letters from people (e.g. Congress of the United States) to Harold Klein
  Proposed Schedule for Meeting
  News about Conflict of Interests by Bertil Lintner in Bangkok
  Australian National University Thai-Yunnan Project News Letter 1994
  Harn Yawnghwe. 1994. "Engaging the Generals. Burma Debate."
  Mya Maung.. 1994. "On the Road to Mandalay."
- Misc. Papers and Correspondences, continued, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Miscellany, 1995 - 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1 A-C)
  Letters from Harold Klein to people (e.g. President Bill Clinton)
  Letters from people (e.g. President Bill Clinton)to Harold Klein
  News of God’s ministry to the Karen people along the Thai/Burma boarder in 1997
  The Karen Voice Vol.1 Issue 1 and 2 in 1998
  Brief News Update from the Thai-Burmese Border
  News from National Coalition Government of the Union of Burma
  News from Bangkok Post in 1997-1998
  CNN World News about Suu Kyi says time needed to judge new Burma Junta
  "No Room for the Chin in Barman Monopolized Politics." 1995 Pu Lian Uk. Burma Debate
- Faxes and correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Parliament of the Commonwealth of Australia Joint Standing Committee on Foreign Affairs, Defense and Trade. 1995. Human Rights Sub-Committee
- Faxes and News, 1994 - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  The BurmaNet News in 1995
  USIS Wireless File
- Interchurch Medical Assistance, INC, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Interchurch Medical Assistance, INC. Annual Report 1985
- Independence Programme (Legal Sized Folder) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Independence Programme by Thra Tha Hto
- U.S. - Burma Foreign Policy, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  International Narcotics Control Strategy Report March 1988
  United States Mission to the United Nations: The U.S. Government is aware of human rights problems in Burma. U.S. policy towards Burma.
  Bureau of Refugee Program: the policy of Thai government which has the right to arrest Burmese students on the frontier and deport them.
  Burma American Fund is being awarded approximately $49,000 for distribution to Burmese refugees along the border.
  Outline of Testimony to be presented before the congressional Human Rights Caucus Hearings on Burma
  Letters from American Karen Agency to the United States Department of State
  U.S. Relations with East Asia
  Harold Klein’s concerns on U.S. foreign policy toward Burma and its minority groups
  Report on the trip to Thailand and Burma from Feb. 9 to 23, 1990 by Sao Ying Sita of Yawnghwe Letter to President George Bush on Sept. 28, 1990
  Letter from Philip R. Mayhew, Director, Office of Thailand and Burma Affairs, stating that The U.S. government encouraged the Royal Thai Government to act against narcotics trafficking in the region but not including sealing the border against the Karen people.
  Perspectives on Economic and Environmental Problems of Burma.
  The Fight for Freedom and Democracy in Burma by Paula Dobriansky.
  Crisis in Burma: Background
  Burma Election
  Statement by the President to ask Burma’s military rulers to release Aung San Suu Kyi
- U.S. Foreign Affairs -- Institutions, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  A letter from Peter Tarnoff in response to Klein’s comments on the article in the Christian Science Monitor
  A letter from Morton I. Abramowitz in response to Human rights abuses situation in Burma.
- Chin National Front, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Chin National Front by John Khaw Kim Thang, President of Chin National Front(July 13 1989)
- Senator Moynihan, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Senate Condemns Human Rights Violations in Burma
  Statement of Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan to Rally for Democracy in Burma
  Letters informing the situations in Burma to U.S. Senate, House of Representatives, and Senator Moynihan
- Senator George Mitchell, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Letter to Senator Mitchell concerning human rights problem in Burma